好啊，那你以什么身份去？
Ok. What defines you better?
麦肯锡的商业顾问还是纳文·班萨尔的女朋友？
Business Consultant at Mckenzie or Naveen Bansal's girlfirend?
拉维 · 拉斯托吉
Ravi Ram Rastogi.
首席执行官、首席技术官、首席营销官
CEO, CTO, CMO
Superentreprenuer.com 创始人
Founder, Superentreprenuer.com
这是我的第八家公司
This is my 8th company
在这之前的那七家呢？
and about those seven before this?
都倒闭了
They were shut down.
我们现在得和评委谈谈
We have to talk to the judges now
纳拉扬·穆西来了吗？
Is Narayan Murthy here yet?
活动工作人员现在已经找到了一个新的替代者
So the event staff has seeked a new replacement now
你怎么能阻止别人参加比赛？
How dare you stop people from entering the competition?
你们能不能让其他团队签一份说明让他们同意你参赛
Can you just get the other teams to sign on a paper That they're okay with you participating
不能去创业公司工作，明白吗？
Don't even think about working in a startup, okay?
你听到了吗？
Do you hear me?
事实上，他没有跟你说实情
Actually, he didn't tell you the whole thing
他想继续创业
He wants to carry on with the startup
好吧，看来我的话在这里没有任何意义
Alright then, it seems like my words have no meaning here
爸爸，给他个机会
爸爸，别走
你已经尽力了，亲爱的
You tried your best dear
我没有放弃
i didn't give up and run back
而是选择站在这里
but i choose to stand here to face you guys
拉杰，你告诉我，我不能在台上卖我的产品
Rajat you told me that I cannot sell my product here on stage
所以我卖自己
Therefore I sold myself
顺便说一嘴，我是普尼特，这是我的名片
by the way i'm Puneet i work for a vc firm, and this is my card
我星期四下午有空，你们星期四有时间吗？
I'm free on thursday afternoon, what are you guys doing on thursday?
相遇只是开始，共处才有进展，能持续通力合作则是成功
所以卡鲁内什邀请他的女朋友过来
So, Karunesh invited his girlfriend over
我跟他说你们睡下层，我睡上层
I told him to use the lower bed frame of the bunk bed and I'll use the upper one
你俩好好玩
You enjoy your privacy
他同意了
He agreed
但是莫汉蒂晚上录了他们的小视频
But Mohanti made an MMS clip of them in the night
然后把视频转发给了我
And forwarded the clip to me
他在早上起来非常生气，开始对我大喊大叫
He became upset in the morning and started yelling at me
这甚至都不是我的错
It wasn't even my fault
听着，拉斯托吉！
Listen Rastogi!
你听说过罗纳德 · 韦恩吗？
Have you heard of Ronald Wayne?
谁？
Who?
罗纳德 · 韦恩，听说过他吗？
Ronald Wayne, ever heard of him?
他是蝙蝠侠的父亲吗？
Was he Batman's father?
他是一个企业家
He was an entrepreneur
40年前，他和他的两个朋友开了一家公司
40 years ago he started a company with his 2 friends
今天，这家公司价值数十亿美元
Today that company is worth billions of dollars
但是没有人认识他
But Nobody knows him
你知道那家公司的名字吗？
Do you know what is the name of that company?
什么名字？
What?
苹果
Apple
每个人都知道史蒂夫 · 乔布斯是谁
Everyone knows who Steve Jobs was
很多人可能也知道史蒂夫 · 沃兹尼亚克
Many people might know about Steve Wozniak too
但是没有人记得第三个人的名字
But no one ever remembers the name of the 3rd guy
而我是第四个人
And look I'm the 4th guy
尤吉说了什么吗？
Yogi said something?
不要因为尤吉说的话而不高兴，他可能是因为脱发而生气
Don't be antsy about what Yogi said, He is probably annoyed with his hairfall
他还能说什么呢？
What could he even say?
总有一天我会痛扁他一顿，他还没看到我粗暴的一面
I'll whoop his sorry ass someday, He hasn't seen my livid side yet
但是杰图呢？
But Jeetu?
我上周在电话里告诉他，下个月一号是银行休假日
I told him on the phone last week that its a bank holiday on the 1st of next month
接着就是是一个周末
Following with a weekend
所以他的薪水可能会晚三四天
So his salary would be 3,4 days overdue
他直接就挂电话了
He disconnected the phone halfway
真没礼貌！
How rude!
你知道我告诉纳文这件事时他说了什么吗？
Do you know what Naveen said when I told him about this?
我很忙，曼达尔，我晚点再和你谈
I'm busy Mandal I'll talk to you later
去给我泡杯茶
Go make some tea for me
这是和首席营销官讲话的方式吗？
Is this a way to talk to a CMO?
根本不是
Not at all
有时候我觉得自己什么都不是，拉斯托吉
Sometimes it feels like that I'm nothing, Rastogi
我是说
I mean
纳文做了产品展示
Naveen gives presentations
杰图负责编码
Jeetu does coding
尤吉去拉供应商
Yogi gets to meet with vendors
没人给我安排正经的事情做
No one gives me any work to do
我觉得我就和空气一样
I think I'm a zero
不要为这些愚蠢的小事烦恼
Don't fret over these stupid little things
看看我，我已经奋斗了14年
Look at me, I've been fighting for 14 years
而你6个月后就能拿到种子资金了
Look at you, who is gonna bag seed funding in just 6 months
而且是来自大西洋资本
From none other than Plutus atlantic
现在只剩下合伙人会议了
You're only left with the partner meeting now
到时候每个人都会承认你在市场上的声誉
Then everyone will acknowledge your reputation in the market
我不需要市场的任何尊重，拉斯托吉
I don't need any respect from the market, Rastogi
我只是想让我的三个朋友尊重我
I just want my 3 friends to respect me
那你就要向他们展示你的奉献精神
Then show them your dedication
为你们的事业奉献你的血汗和泪水
Give your blood, sweat and tears to this startup
多做一些事情，他们就会开始尊重你
Go the extra mile and they'll start respecting you
我还要怎么向他们展示我的奉献精神呢？
How else am I going to show them dedication?
我一周五天为杰图鞍前马后
I am the one who works his ass off for Jeetu 5 days a week
到了晚上我已经筋疲力尽了，但我还是会为尤吉和纳文做晚饭
I get exhausted by the evening but I still cook dinner for Yogi and Naveen
我整天带着这个U盘走来走去
I go around all day with this pen drive clinging to me
如果这样奉献的还不够，那我真不知道该怎么做了
If this isn't enough dedication then I don't know what is
这个U盘是怎么回事？
What's with this pen drive?
公司所有的秘密
All the company's secrets
所有重要的文件
Everything important to the company...
都在这个U盘里面
...is in this pen drive
这个U盘能使我们的公司成为大公司
This is what will make our company big
每次会议后我都会更新
I update it after every meeting
我去年在纽约，花了5美元买来的
I was in New York last year, got it from there for $5
但我确信这个5块钱的U盘有一天会给我们带来50亿美元的收入
But I'm sure that this same device will get us 5 Billion dollars one day
你怎么不喝这个？
Why don't you drink this? huh?
放轻松
Yeah Chill out!
不不不不
No no no no
我只喝啤酒.
I will drink only beer...
我喝这种劣质饮料会不舒服
I have a digestion problem with these inferior quality drinks
喝吧，这没什么不好的
Drink up, there's nothing wrong with it
特别推荐
This is Rastogi's special
这是我们第六次创业时卖的东西
This is what we were selling in our 6th startup venture
科伦坡海啸
Colombo Tsunami
这个名字起得不好
The title is a little insensitive
否则老虎环球公司绝对会给我们投钱
Otherwise Tiger Global would've been onboard just like that
就冲你这句话，我就喝一小口
Just for you, I'll have one sip
好吧，两口
Okay, two
杰图老婆超性感
Jeetu's wife is so hot man
真的吗？
Really?
而且很有教养
And so cultured
我不知道我妈在哪里找到这些蠢女人，还坚持要我去见她们
I don't know where my mom finds these dumb bimbos and insists me to meet them
我曾经问过一个女孩，“你喜欢《阿凡达》的什么? ”
I once asked a girl, "What do you like about Avatar?"
她说: “拉杰什·坎纳(Avtaar 演员)太可爱了.”
She said, "Rajesh Khanna(*Actor in Avtaar) is so cute"
这都什么鬼啊？
I mean what the fuck girls?
抱歉，我两分钟后回来，憋不住了
Sorry, I'll be back in 2 minutes, Nature's call
快点回来
Come back in a jiffy
你得付账
You have to pay the bill
当然，我玩得很开心
Of course, I had a good time
谢谢你！
Thank you!
不，不，谢谢你才对
No no, thank you
如果他们问你期望薪资多少，告诉他们给你点时间考虑一下
If they ask you about the salary, tell them to give you a minute to think
告诉hr你自己开车上下班
Tell the HR that you'll manage your own transportation
他们会非常高兴的
They'll be as pleased as punch
伙计们，优步已经接单了，五分钟后到
Guys, Uber is booked Cab will be here in Five
快点，纳文! 我们要再确认一下
Hurry-up Naveen! We have to double check
如果不是因为要升副总，我才不会来
If it weren't for my VP promotion, I wouldn't be fighting for you
我这么做是因为你们的产品很有前途
I'm doing this because your product is promising
别抱怨了，我从昨晚就准备好了
Stop yammering, I've been ready since last night
我系着领带睡觉
I even slept wearing the tie
杰图，过来
Jeetu, come along now
等一下
Hold on a minute
检查衣柜的抽屉，里面一定有一个白色的手提包
Check in the closet drawer, there must be a white carry bag
是的，有卡利亚尼纱丽的那个
Yes the one with Kalyani sari
你能找到你的证件、护照、支票簿和其他文件.
You'll find your certificate, passport, checkbook and every document in it.
他在干什么？
What is he up to?
她老婆今天要面试一份工作
Soumya is interviewing for a job today
他已经絮叨两个小时了
He's been blabbering about his postmodern post-marriage love story for 2 hours
嘿，尤吉
Hey Yogi!
你看见我的U盘了吗？
Have you seen my pen drive?
哪一个？
Which one?
跟那个一样的
The same with...
尤吉已经做了两三个备份了
Yogi has already taken 2 or 3 backups of the presentation
喂，听着
Oh hello!
六个备份
Six backups
不，不在这里
No its not here
曼达尔你给我坐下
Mandal, sit your ass down
曼达尔，坐下
Mandal, sit down there
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
纳文你怎么回事？
Naveen, what the hell is going on?
纳文，过来！你在这里干什么？
Naveen, come along What are you even doing here?
我只能睡4个小时，至少让我洗洗脸
I could only sleep for 4 hours, At least let me wash my face
我们今天终于要拿到资金了
We're finally getting the funding today
我的运气在闪耀，我的脸也应该闪耀，不是吗？
My luck is shining and so should my face, No?
你们这些家伙太小看这次会议了
You guys are taking this meeting very lightly
这么跟你说吧
I'm telling you since day 1...
就算公司里的每个人都喜欢你的主意，那也跟你能不能拿到钱没关系
...everyone in the firm is liking your idea but this has nothing to do with seed funding
重要的是巴德瓦伊喜不喜欢
All that matters is whether Bhardwaj likes it or not
我们只剩下30分钟了，来吧，快过来
We've just 30 minutes left, Come along now come on come on
你们就快迟到了
You guys are so tardy...
把它关掉
...Turn it off
好了，我坐下了
Alright I'm sitting down
不，不，起来
No no get up
一定要准时，寺庙可以晚点去
Just be punctual, Temples can wait
杰图！
Jeetu!
好吧，我挂了
Alright I'm hanging up
听着，早餐在冰箱里，记得吃，好吗？
Hey listen, breakfast is in the fridge Eat properly, Okay?
哦，还有甜酸奶，它会给你带来好运
Oh and have some sweet yoghurt, it'll bring you good luck
一切顺利
All the best
替我祝她好运
Wish her good luck for me
纳文祝你一切顺利
Naveen wishes you all the best
也替我祝福她
Wish her for me too
行了，别bb了
Just say it simultaneously and be done with it guys
不，没什么，普尼特祝你一切顺利.我晚点再打给你
No its nothing, Puneet wishes you all the best. I'll talk to you later
对不起
Sorry
你们知道吗? 理想情况下我根本不该来这里
Do you guys know that Ideally I shouldn't even be here
我为什么来这里？
Why did I come here?
最重要的是...
The most important...
你们要和谁见面？
With whom are you guys meeting?
太平洋资本的资深合伙人安吉·巴特瓦吉
Ankit Bhardwaj, senior partner Plutus Atlantic
你们知道他是谁吗？
Do you guys have any idea who is he?
在风投圈子里，他被称为迈达斯·巴德瓦吉
He's known as Midas Bhardwaj in the VC circles
是迈迪斯还是迈达斯？
Is it Midas or Midaas?
你闭嘴
Shut up you benighted fool
他的投资组合中有市值1700多万美元的公司，而他的反投资组合中却没有一家
He has 17 multi million dollar companies in his portfolio and zero in his anti portfolio
什么是反投资组合？
What's anti portfolio?
什么是投资者的投资组合？
What is investor's portfolio?
他选择投资的公司都很成功
The companies he chose to fund and they became successful
那么它的反义词是什么？
Then what is its ANTI?
那些他选择不投资的公司，却取得了成功
The companies he chose not to fund and yet they became successful
没错
Exactly
巴德瓦伊在他的个人资料中没有任何反投资组合的标题
Bhardwaj doesn't have any header of anti-portfolio in his profile
如果他今天拒绝你的提议...
Now if he rejects your idea today...
记住我的话，在孟买或班加罗尔，就不会有人看好你们了
...then mark my words no one will give a flying fuck to your idea in Bombay or Bangalore
那么既然你们不想去德里，我也不想永远做一个分析师
Now you don't want to go to Delhi and I don't want to remain as an analyst forever
所以让我们一起专注这件事，好吗？
So let's focus on it together, Okay?
在那个房间里的30分钟...
Those 30 minutes inside that room...
决定你们上天堂还是下地狱
...can take your lives in two completely opposite direction
你有一个令人印象深刻的产品，你做了很多辛苦的工作
You have an impressive product and you did a lot of elbow grease on it
就是这样
This is what it boils down to
还有进去的时候别忘了先好好舔他
And don't forget to lick his balls the minute you enter there
好了，出租车来了我们走吧
Alright guys, cab is here Let's leave
纳文，把你的衬衫扣子系好
Naveen, button your shirt to the neck
曼达尔，我找不到
Mandal- I couldn't find it
小朋友们，快点！
Puneet- Guys hurry up!
杰图-让我穿上鞋子
Jeetu- Let me put on my shoes
杰图 -曼达尔 你又穿我的袜子了？
Jeetu- Mandal did you wear my socks again?
- 曼达尔 - 不，我穿的是自己的
Mandal- No, I'm wearing my own
杰图，你的演示版准备好了吗？
Jeetu, your demo is ready?
那么Facebook登录呢？
What about FB login?
哦，还没有
Oh, not yet
我在出租车上做
I'll do it in the cab
好吧
Yeah okay
我应该打领带吗？
Should I wear a tie?
你穿内裤去都行
You can wear boxers in their let alone tie
安基特，纳文和他的团队
Ankit, Naveen and team
你好，我是安基特
hi, i'm Ankit. -Naveen
你们要喝点什么吗？-不用了
you guys want anything？tea？coffee？
我看了你的演讲，非常发人深省
Sir, I saw your TED Talk it was very thought provoking
哪个演讲? 加利福尼亚还是温哥华？
Which one? California or Vancouver?
两个都看了
Both of them
真的吗? 下个月才去温哥华
Really? Vancouver is next month
普尼特，你要点什么吗？
Puneet, you want anything?
很抱歉，但是...
I'm sorry guys but...
不，不，没关系，你吃你的
No no its okay feel free
早餐没吃，现在我妻子要我吃燕麦作为惩罚
Missed the breakfast, now my wife is making me eat oats as a punishment
你们结婚了吗？
You guys are married?
只有我结婚了，先生
Only me sir
那你们有女朋友了吗
Oh, so girlfriends?
先生，纳文有女朋友
Sir, Naveen has one
那么安基特，我们要现在开始演示吗？
So Ankit, should we start the presentation?
纳文
Naveen
不，等一下
Uh no wait a second
等一下
Hold on for a minute
伙计们...
Guys...
今天我从班加罗尔回来的路上……
...on my way back from bangalore today
我必须说这个想法有很大的潜力
And I must say the idea has lot of potential
你们提到的目标是相当现实并且是实现的
The targets that you guys have mentioned are quite realistic and achievable
而且收入模式也令人印象深刻
And the revenue model is also very impressive
谢谢，先生
Thank you sir
但是...
BUT...
我要强调但是
And I say the BUT in capital letters
就在几天前，有几个人给我介绍了...
Couple of days back, few guys presented me...
想法和目标与你们完全一致
...the exact same idea with the exact same targets
并且收入模式也完全一致
and the exact same revenue models
我不知道这是怎么回事
Now I'm not sure how this has happened
等一下，安吉特
Hold on a minute, Ankit
我和这些人在一起已经三四个星期了，我非常确信这个想法是他们原创的
I've been with these guys for last 3,4 weeks now I'm pretty convinced that its their original idea...
我不认为他们会剽窃或者...
I don't think they have stolen it or..
不，不，我没有指责任何人
No no I'm not accusing anybody
即使对我来说，这也是一个特殊的情况
Even for me this is a unique situation
但是两个团队有着完全相同的想法.
But two teams with exactly the same idea..
不可能只是巧合
can't just be a coincidence
但是我们从大学起就有这个想法...
But we have this idea since college...
抱歉
sorry,sorry
但是安吉特，我们从大学就开始研究这个了
But Ankit we've been on this since college
如果你想看的话，我也可以把我们内部的沟通邮件给你看
If you want I can also show you our chat and conversation over mail
我们已经计划了3年
We've been planning this for 3 years
老弟，我不是侦探
Guys guys I'm not a detective
我是一个投资者
I'm an investor
同样的产品被两个不同的团队两次推荐给我
And the same product has been pitched to me twice by 2 different teams
先生，你能透露他们的名字吗？
Sir, I mean can you disclose their names?
好吧.
Well...
现在我不能透露他们的名字
I can't reveal their names at this point of time
还有...
And...
这对你们来说就有了一些改变
This changes few things for you guys
让我来解释一下投资到底是如何运作的
Let me explain you how the investment process really works
在这片未知的海洋里
So, in this sea of unknown
你们在这个岛上
You guys are sitting here on this island
带着你们满意的创业想法
Comfortably with your idea
我们把这个岛叫做.
Let's call this island..
舒适区
Comfort zone
我在这个岛上
And I'm here on this island
神奇的事情发生了
Where magic happens
这就是大公司形成的地方
This is where big companies are formed
现在你们必须到这里来
Now you guys have to reach here
有两种选择
There are 2 options
一.
One..
你走出你的舒适区，开始游泳
You step out of your comfort zone and start swimming
你将不得不面对不确定的浪潮
You'll have to face the waves of uncertainty, the tides of sacrifice
命运无法预测的气候变化
The unpredictable climate change of destiny
还有... 我不确定你能不能撑到那儿
And... I'm not sure if you're gonna make it to there
但幸运的是，你们还有另一个选择
But luckily for you guys, there's another option
我有一条船，就叫它小金船吧
I have a boat named as $$ money
我可以把这艘船送给你们
I can send this boat to you guys
你可以上我的船，很容易就能到达这个岛
You can hop into that boat and can easily make it to this island
但这就是问题所在
But herein lies the problem
你们岛屿的复制品就在海的这一端
A replica of your island is at this end of the sea
而我只能把我的船只送往一个方向
And I can send my boat in only one direction
但是，先生，既然这是我们最初的想法，我们不应该得到投资吗？
But sir shouldn't we get the investment since its our original idea?
但是……
But guys..
因为这船是我的
Because I own the boat
只有我能做出这样的选择
Only I can make that choice
虽然听起来很不幸
And as unfortunate as it may sound
但是现在决定权
The ball right now is..
完全在我的手上
..completely in my court
我知道这是机密，所以我才打电话给你
I know its confidential, that's why I called you
你的晋升要出问题? 那我晚点给你打电话.好的，再见
Your promotion's on stake? I'll call you later then. Okay bye
伙计们，巴德瓦伊不会透露对方的名字
Guys, thing is that Bhardwaj is not gonna disclose the names
班加罗尔的团队也不开口
And Bangalore team is also uncommunicative
实际上很难知道他们是谁
Realistically its tough to get the names
普尼特，你能想出办法来吗？
Puneet, can you work something out?
我正在努力，但还有一个问题
I'm trying but there's another problem
巴德瓦伊后天就要去迪拜了
Bhardwaj is leaving for Dubai day after tomorrow
然后呢？
What then?
我会在明天的第二次会议上解决这个问题，别担心，我有一些关系
I'll sort it out in a 2nd meeting tomorrow, Don't worry I have some contacts
我会打电话给他们，然后再打给你
I'll call them and get back to you
该死！
Shit man
你确定普尼特没有泄露我们的想法？
Are you sure that Puneet didn't leak our idea?
不，不，他自己的晋升危在旦夕，不是他干的
No no his own promotion is on stake, he didn't do it
史瑞雅怎么了? 你知道我今天要开会
What's the matter Shreya? You know I have a meeting today
那你为什么一遍又一遍地给我打电话？
Then why are you calling me over and over?
我遇到了一个大问题，我现在不能来
I'm facing a huge problem here, I can't come right now
但至少告诉我怎么了？
But at least tell me what's the matter?
好的，我来了，好的，我马上到
Alright I'm coming, Yeah I'll be there
伙计们，我20分钟后回来，如果普尼特有什么消息给我打电话
Guys I'll be back in 20, Call me if Puneet comes up with anything
我们应该列一张嫌疑人的名单
We should make a list of probable suspects
那会有帮助吗？
Would that help?
我有很多反盗窃的经验
I have a lot of experience with larceny
我读 MBA 一年级的时候，有人隔天就会偷我的水桶
When I was in MBA 1st year, someone used to steal my water bucket on alternate days
所以我列了一个表并应用了基本定理，结果发现罪魁祸首是我的舍友
So I formed a list and applied base theorem, Turned out culprit was from my wing
我有预感是我们认识的人
I have a hunch its somebody we know
曼达尔，你的U盘呢？
Mandal, where's your pen drive?
我不知道，找不到了
I don't know, couldn't find it
我上周末遇到了拉斯托吉，从那以后...
I met Rastogi last weekend, since then its...
操！
FUCK!
每个演示和模板都在里面
Each and every demo and templates were in it
现在就打给他
Call that Rastogi now
快点，你个白痴
Call him you moron
对不起
I'm sorry
开免提
Put it on speaker
他在班加罗尔，他就是在那里偷走我们的想法的
He's in Bangalore, That's where he pitched our idea
妈的，我们现在一定要去班加罗尔吗？
Shit, do we have to go to Bangalore now?
想去班加罗尔吗？
Wanna go to Bangalore motherfucker?
是的，拉斯托吉可能正坐在咖啡店里，对着你的名字打飞机
Yeah Rastogi might be sitting in a coffee shop, jerking off to your name
请不要这样跟我说话
Please don't talk to me like that
我他妈打死你，你个傻逼
I'll beat your ass you cunt face
你要做的就是什么都不做
All you had to do Mandal was nothing Nothing
你的工作就是什么都不做，然而你还是搞砸了
That's all you had to do and you shit in that too
我从第一天开始就跟纳文说我们不能把他算进去
I've been telling Naveen since day 1 that we shouldn't include him
我可以容忍他的零贡献但我不能容忍他挖坑
I can tolerate his zero contribution But I can't put up with his negative contribution
本来我们现在应该拿到投资意向书了
We would've gotten the term sheet by now
谁给你的权利来搅乱我们的计划？
Who gave you the right to fuck with our lives?
尤吉，你为什么要这么说，兄弟？
Yogi, why are you speaking like that, bro?
我已经很内疚了
I'm already feeling guilty
我不是故意的
I didn't do it on purpose
是，你不是故意的，知道为什么吗？
Yeah you can't do it on purpose, you know why?
因为你是个混蛋
Because you're a cunt
尤吉，够了，别说了
Yogi its enough Hold on a second
你是个贱货，全世界都知道你是个贱货，你自己也知道你是个贱货
You're a cunt The whole world knows that you're a cunt And you also know that you are a cunt
别这样跟我说话，尤吉
Stop talking to me like that Yogi
是的，我知道我犯了错误.
Yes I know I made a mistake.
但我们是朋友...
But we are friends...
是吗？
Really?
那么除了我们之外，你的其他朋友呢？
Then where are your other friends besides us?
你为什么偏偏找拉斯托吉一起喝酒？
And why did you find Rastogi, of all people to drink beer with?
你知道为什么总是你的水桶被偷吗？
Do you know why it was always your bucket that got stolen?
因为你就是个贱货
Because you're a pussy
你是个大傻逼
You're the biggest douchebag out there
我们所遭受的这种折磨是对你这种贱人加入我们队伍的惩罚
This ordeal that we are suffering is a punishment for involving cunts like you in our team
那好吧
Okay then
你不用再为我受苦了
You won't have to suffer because of me again
和你们合作很愉快
It was great working with you guys
我不干了
I quit
曼达尔...
Mandal...
尤吉，你不应该...
Yogi you shouldn't have...
- 曼达尔...-赶紧滚
- Mandal... - Get lost
做出明智的决定，永远不要回来，你这该死的输不起的家伙
Take a stand in your life just this once and don't ever come back you damn sore loser
你都干了些什么，尤吉？
What are you doing Yogi?
史瑞亚
Shreya
等一下等一下
Hold on a minute Just a sec
阿姨，你能把它移开吗？
Aunty, can you move it?
你叫谁阿姨呢？
Who are you calling aunty?
大姐，你能把它移开吗？
Madam, can you please move it?
我们去那边
Come on that side
你这是在闹什么，你从来没有这么不讲道理过
What is this nonsense? you've never been so unreasonable
我正在开会，你一直打电话过来
I was in the middle of a meeting and you kept calling over & over
还记得里约热内卢吗? 我参加的那个面试？
Remember Rio? That job interview I had?
怎么了? 你不是已经拒绝了.
Yeah, what about that? You rejected it.
是的，但是他们的伦敦办事处有新的空缺
Yes but they have new vacancies in their London office
他们希望我尽快赶过去
And they want me there ASAP
事实上，我必须在今晚之前去他们那报到
Infact, I have to get back to them by tonight, latest.
要去多久？
For how long?
我以为你在这里很开心？
I thought you were happy here?
我当然很开心，但是...
I am... Ofcourse I am, but...
纳文，这是一个梦幻城市的理想工作
Naveen, its a dream job in a dream city
这是一生中只有一次的机会
Its like a once in a lifetime opportunity
你决定了吗？
Have you decided then?
我不知道
I don't know
我真不敢相信我要在...
I can't believe I have to choose between...
我的未来和我们的未来之间做选择
My future and our future
我不想一个人做出这样的选择
And I don't want to make that choice all by myself
现在我能说什么呢，这是你的决定
What can I say now, its your decision
如果你是我，你会怎么做？
What would you have done if you were in my place?
我想你应该去
I think you should go
曼达尔手机关机了
Mandal's phone is switched off
你为什么对他发那么大火，尤吉？
Why do you flip out so much Yogi?
他哪儿也不会去，喝了几杯啤酒就回家了
He's not gonna go anywhere, he'll be home after a couple of beers
尤吉，如果他做了什么蠢事你负的起责任吗？
Yogi, He's Mandal Will you take responsibility if he did anything stupid?
混蛋回来了
There's your asshole
一定是桑亚，我让她面试结束后来这里
Must be Soumya, I told her to come here after the interview
听着，闭上你的臭嘴，我不想让她被你吓到
Listen, keep your trap shut, I don't want her to get in a stew
我通过了
I got it
面试很顺利，他们会给我发offer，下周入职
Interview was amazing, they are gonna send me an offer letter and I'm gonna join by next week
恭喜你桑亚... 恭喜
Congrats Soumya... Congrats
对不起，尤吉，我没看见你
I'm sorry Yogi, I didn't see you
不，不，你们继续，我去里面
No no, you guys carry on I'll be inside
不，不，没关系的，这个给你
No no, its allright Actually this is for you
里面是什么，糖果吗？
What's in it? sweets?
不，这些是打印店寄来的名片，他们早上送来的
No, these are visiting cards from Vista prints, they delievered it in the morning
实际上他告诉我以前的卡质量很差，所以...
Actually he told me that the quality of previous cards was quite shoddy so...
你们会议开得怎么样？
How did the meeting go?
非常棒，演示相当不错 -演示非常棒的，所以...
It was great, presentation went pretty well Demo was amazing so..
总之我们做得很好，他很喜欢
We pitched it well, he liked it
是的，聊得很愉快
Yeah meeting was great
你和爸爸谈过了吗？
Did you talk to Dad?
没有
No
其实只有在我爸问到你和你爸的时候才能聊几句
Actually I could talk to my Dad only He was asking about you and dad
我有预感爸爸知道这件事
I have a hunch that dad knows about it
所以，我想我应该先和你谈谈，然后再和爸爸谈
So, I think first I should talk to you and then dad
为什么，你应该先和爸爸谈谈
Why? you should talk to dad first
你们是怎么分辨出说的是谁爸爸呢？
How can you married couple can tell the difference between whose dad we're talking about
好吧，我会跟爸爸说的，但是我应该怎么说？
Okay, I'll talk to dad but should I say?
说你经常说的话
Say what you always say
我知道我们不同意他的意见，但我们不能不尊重他.你应该给他打电话
I know we disagree with him but we don't disrespect him. You should call him
普尼特来电话了
Puneet is calling
普尼特，我是尤吉
Yeah, hi Puneet Its Yogi here
喂，听着，尤吉，我不能直接找到名字
Yeah look Yogi, I couldn't find the name directly
但是我这有巴德瓦伊上周的日程安排
But I have Bhardwaj's last week schedule right in front of me
我有他以前所有会面的详细情况
I have the details of all of his previous meetings
你能查一下他是否和拉斯托吉见过面吗？
Can you check if he had any meeting with Rastogi?
查查有没有叫拉斯托吉的
Yeah, check for a Rastogi
不，不，拉斯托吉有一个 r，是的
No no Rastogi with an R, yes
没有拉斯托吉
There's no Rastogi here Yogi
没有拉斯托吉？
No Rastogi?
你按字母顺序检查一下? 从 a 开始挨个念一遍
Why don't you check alphabetically? and tell me the names starting from A
这里有将近80个名字，我已经交叉核对过了
There are almost 80 names here, I have already cross checked the list
他们要么是大公司，要么是已经注资的创业公司
Either they are big companies or already funded startups
只剩下一个没有名字的，只有一个电子邮箱
There's only one slot left with no name but just an Email ID
什么是电子邮箱？
What is the Email ID?
某种特殊的身份，是的...
Some peculiar ID, yes...
地下城主@hotmail. com 地下城和主人之间有一个下划线
dungeon_master@hotmail.com there's an underscore between dungeon and master
我操！！！
FUCK!!!!!!!!!!
哦，操！
Oh fuck!
你为什么选择这个地方来谈论这么重要的事情
Why did you choose this place to talk about such an important matter
我们本可以去餐厅聊的
We could've gone to a restaurant
也许是因为我想跟你走一次红毯
Maybe because I wanted to walk down the aisle with you once
很好，你的幽默感还在
Good to know, that your sense of humour is still intact
你的“事业第一”思想仍然保持着我也很欣慰
And good to see, that your "career comes first" ideology is still intact
纳文！
Naveeeeeen!
说出来吧
Please say it
只要说一次我爱你，没有你我活不下去，请不要离开我
Just say it once that I love you, I can't live without you, please don't leave me
史瑞雅，我爱你，没有你我活不下去
Shreya, I love you, I can't live without you
但是请你走吧
But please go
我们会想办法的
We'll try and figure out something
比如什么？
Like what?
异地恋？
Long distance?
你知道那是行不通的
You know that never works
我可能再也不会回来了
I might never come back
你不能搬到那里，我也不能呆在这里
You can't move there and I can't be here
我们不要把问题简单化，好吗？
Let's not try to take the easy way out, okay?
还有时间，我给你一枚硬币，你去找个审判室做个决定
There's still time. I'll give you a coin, make the trial room your jury room
这改变不了什么
That is not gonna change anything
我太了解你了，这就是问题所在
I know you too well you know thats the problem
你知道吗，你变得越来越可预测了
You're getting very predictable you know
你说不动我的，别说了
You're not instigating me, please stop trying
听着，真的吗? ，你要放我走? ，我？
Listen, really? You're letting me go? me?
你要让这个，这个，这个，还有那个走了？
You're letting this and this and these and that go?
你知道得到这个组合有多难吗？
Do you realize how tough it is to get this combination?
不是难，而是不可能的
It won't be tough, it will be impossible
但这是你的工作，你必须要去
But its your job You have to do it
你的工作是你死后唯一长久存在的东西
You know that your work is the only thing that will be here long after you're gone
纳文，那只是一种比喻
Naveen, that's just a figure of speech
我们不是甘地，牛顿或者莎士比亚
We're not Gandhi, Newton or Shakespeare
我们的工作只是一起白头到老，就这么简单
Our work is just gonna get buried with our graves Its as simple as that
不是的，史瑞雅
That is not true Shreya
等一下
Hold on a minute
这是什么？
What is this?
你的头
Your head
认真点
What nonsense?
告诉我这是什么？
Go on tell me what's this?
这是一个瓶子，怎么了？
Its a bottle, what else?
谁造出来的？
Who built it?
我怎么知道？
How would I know?
你知道1000年前人类住在山洞里的时候...
You know when man used to live in caves 1000 years ago...
你在开玩笑吗? ，我们要回到一千年前，是吗？
Are you kidding me? We are going that back, are we?
是的，听我说
Yeah we are going that back Listen to me
山洞里的人觉得从河里取水很费劲
He would find it arduous to draw water from the rivers
有人就用树叶做了一个装水的容器，但不耐用
Then someone made a water container made of leaves But it wasn't durable
然后有人注意到，把湿土暴露在阳光直射下会变成粘土
Then someone noticed that exposing wet soil to direct sunlight turns it into clay
所以有人用这种粘土做了一个罐子
And then someone else made a pot from that very clay
但这也不是长久之计
But that wasn't durable either
后来有人发明了塑料
Then someone invented plastic
有人就认为塑料可以做成耐用的容器
And then someone else thought plastic would make a durable container
然后有人设计了它的形状，另一个人把它变成透明的
Then someone else designed its shape, another person made it transparent
有人设计了盖子，有人设计了拧盖子的线路
Someone discovered the caps, and someone designed the threads of the cap
有人建造了一个制造瓶子的工厂
And someone made a whole factory to manufacture bottles
成千上万的人工作，就为了制造这些瓶子
in which thousands of people work just to make these bottles
成千上万的人工作了这么多年，史瑞雅，所以我们今天有瓶子可以用
Millions of people have been working for so many years, Shreya so that we can make use of these bottles
也许我们不想承认，但是...
Maybe we don't acknowledge it but...
一代又一代人的工作成果还保留在世上
...there work is still here long after they're gone
这只是一个瓶子，史瑞雅
And this is just a bottle, Shreya
看看你的周围，你正站在人类工作历史的博物馆
look at your surroundings You're standing at a museum of human work history
看看周围
Just look around
还有什么更好的地方能证明你的观点呢？
And what better place to prove your point, right?
你总是对的，班萨尔先生
Like always you're right Mr. Bansal
你会想我吗？
Will you miss me?
也许在某些寂寞的夜晚
On some lonely nights, maybe
你呢？
You?
每天晚上都想
Every night
死鬼
Pervert prick
好吧，我得做点什么
Well, I'll have to do something
答应我，在你开始和别人约会之前，给我三个月的时间
Promise me that you'll give me a window of 3 months before you start seeing someone else
好吧，你也不要在伦敦疯狂发自拍
Okay, and you also don't go on a selfie spree once you're in London
好的
Okay done
我们是灵魂伴侣，对吧？
We were sort of a soulmates type, right?
如果我在这里，我们肯定会结婚
We would be marrying for sure if I had been here
感谢上帝，没有让这种事发生
Thank god it didn't happen
所以，严格来说，我们要分手了
So, technically we're breaking up
我们从来没有涉及到技术细节，宝贝
We never got into technicalities baby
不，我这么说是因为...
No, I'm saying that because...
这是分手炮了
...it makes for a breakup sex for one last time
当然
Ofcourse
我今晚要回家一个星期，等我回来再说
I'm leaving for home tonight for one week, We'll get to that once I'm back
不管怎样，我下周就要走了...
Anyway, I'll be leaving next week...
好吧听着
Okay, listen
我想我该走了
I think I should go now
我晚上还要赶飞机，还没开始收拾行李呢
I have a flight to catch in the evening and I haven't even started packing yet
好吗？
Okay?
我明天再打电话给你
I'll talk to you tomorrow
纳文...
Listen...
拿着这个
Here, keep this
- 这是什么?-密码1767
- What's this? - 1767 (*PIN no.)
你为什么给我你的信用卡? 别闹？
Why are you giving me your credit card? what nonsense?
不要在我面前逞英雄，我知道你的经济状况
Don't be a hero in front of me, I know your financial situation
食品杂货我管你一个月，好吗？
Groceries are on me for a month, okay?
这不是礼物，我是借给你的
And its not a gift, I'm giving you a loan
你可以以后再付我钱
You can pay me later
好吗？
Okay?
纳文
Naveen
纳文，别这样，别在这儿好吗？
Naveen don't do this, not here, okay?
你知道我不能就这样离开
You know I can't leave like this
怎么了？
What happened?
为了创业，我不得不做出很多牺牲
I had to do a lot of sacrifices for the startup
我放弃了一份体面的工作，体面的薪水，良好的生活条件
I gave up a decent job, decent salary, good stantard of living
这些都无所谓
And it never bothered me
但是现在你为我的工作牺牲了
But now you are sacrificing for my work
这让我很心疼
It hurts me a lot
疼得要命
Hurts like hell
但是如果不疼，那就不算牺牲了，不是吗？
But if didn't hurt then its not gonna be a sacrifice, right?
总有一天你会登上时代杂志的封面
And there'll be a time when you're gonna be on the cover of TIME magazine
那这一切都值了
then this'll all seem worth it
但是一定要确保这一点，好吗？
But just please make sure that happens, okay?
为了我们，好吗？
For us, Okay?
再见，我会打电话给你
Bye, I'll call you
我说我最近怎么收到很多生发广告的电子邮件
Thats why I was getting a lot of Emails lately regarding Hair therapy
他从6个月前就开始整我了
He's been fucking with me since 6 months
你之前还打算用他来取代我？
And you were gonna replace me with him?
是的，因为没钱
Yeah because of financial crunch
你要尝试道歉，尤吉
Learn to apologize, Yogi
不，道歉太蠢了
Nah, apologies are stupid
但我敢肯定，当我踩在他们屁股上的时候，这些混蛋会道歉的
But I'm sure these assholes will be grovelling when I'll stamp their asses with my shoes
尤吉，拜托，你冷静一下
Yogi please, you ought to be calm
你从早上起就心情不好，让我来处理吧
You're in a black mood since morning, let me handle this with patience
好吧，但是如果他们激怒我，我他妈搞死他们
Okay but if they aggravated me, I'll fuck their shit up
他们只有17岁，我要劝劝他们
They are only 17 years old kids, I'll talk some sense into them
好吧，你先说，说不通我在动手，好吗? ，我们走
Allright, you talk and I'll kick Okay? lets go
他们很幸运，我今天没穿运动鞋
And they're lucky that I didn't put on my woodland shoes today
这里到底发生了什么？
The fuck happened here?
上次那些笨蛋在哪里？
Where are those blockheads from last time?
- 那是什么?-看起来是屎
What's that? Looks like someone took a shit here
来吧，快点，我们做正事
Come on hurry up, lets do our business
来了老弟，我们等你半天了
Come Yogi, come we were waiting for you
你们知道我们要来吗？
you guys knew we were coming?
不，不，我们只是喜欢每天晚上8点到10点这样坐着
No no, we just like to sit like this everynight from 8 to 10
我们这里有大门的监控
We got a hold of main gate's CCTV surveilance right here
宝贝，你的华丽出场可以了，我能走了吗？
Baby, you got your dramatic entry, Can I go now?
好吧
Yeah okay
你晚上会带我去泡温泉，对吗？
you're taking me to spa in the evening, right?
班娜丽，我在工作
Banali, I'm working
小伙子们...
Look guys...
你知道我们为什么来这里
You know why we are here
我们费了很大力气才创造出那种产品
It took a lot of elbow grease for us to make that product
你们犯了一个错误，这也是违法的
You guys did a mistake and its illegal too
你们只是大学生，我们不会告你的
And you guys are just kids in college, we're not gonna lodge a complaint against you
你只是犯了个错误，没关系.
You made a mistake, its alright.
你只需要打电话给巴德瓦伊，跟他说退出
You just need to call Bhardwaj and backout
放松，我们不会对你采取任何行动
Relax, we're not taking any action against you
杰图，这家伙很可爱
Jeetu, this guy is very cute
如果你追踪这个 IP 地址，你会查到穆伦德的网吧
If you'll track the IP address, you'll get Mulund's cyber cafe
你没有任何筹码
You ain't got shit on me
听着，我们有证据表明这是我们的主意
Look, we have all the proofs which claims that this is our idea
我告诉你们是为了你们好，你们都上大学了
I'm telling you for your own good, you guys are in college
当你父母知道这件事的时候，你会有麻烦的
You'll get into trouble when your parents get to know about it
我不怕我的父母
i'm not scared of my parents
如果我们的父母有足够的时间来管我们...
If our parents had enough time to reprove us...
那你就不会和我这样的小屁孩打交道了
...then you wouldn't be dealing with a brat like me
等一下，杰图，把你的电话给我
Hold on a second, Jeetu Give me your phone
把你的电话给我，我会告诉这些混蛋该打给谁.救护车还是巴德瓦伊？
Give me your phone and I'll tell these fucks who to call. Ambulance or Bhardwaj?
把你手机给我
Give me your phone
你见过雷迪吗？
have you met Reddy?
雷迪非常喜欢视频聊天
Reddy was very fond of video chatting
他在陌陌上哄骗了一个保加利亚女孩
He cajoled a Bulgarian girl on omegle
然后每天晚上他都会和她视频聊天做一些下流的事...
And then every night he used to skype with her, doing some nasty nasty...
但他不知道我录下了所有的视频
But little did he know that I was recording all the chats
有一天...
And one day...
我把所有的视频聊天都上传到了网上
I uploaded all the video chats on the internet
我费了好大劲才把那些视频撤下来
It took him a lot of grovelling to do for me to take those videos down
这可是我最好的朋友
And this is my best friend we're talking about
而你是我父亲第三个堂兄的共同朋友
While you are a mutual friend of my father's third cousin
你会在今晚一点上线，对吗？
You gonna login at 1 AM tonight, right?
斯维特拉娜是个单身母亲
Svetlana is a single mom
在很多方面也是一个企业家
And also an entrepreneur in many ways
41G的视频，雷迪刚刚为它买了一个新的硬盘
41gb material, Reddy just got a new hard drive for it
在这些欲火中烧的日子里真的太感谢她了，帮我跟她说声谢谢
It helped a lot during dry day, say her thanks for me
别动哦，尤吉
Dare not touch, Yogi
我的新电脑有免费的路由器
Got a free router with my new computer
想试试上传速度吗？
Wanna test the upload speed?
老哥们，拜托了
Guys, please...
比尔坑了史蒂夫，创建了微软
Bill stomped on Steve to create Microsoft
所以你们是谁？
Then who are you?
滚吧
Go back the same way you came
如果你试图联系巴德瓦伊.
If you even tried to contact Bhardwaj...
那么尤吉和斯维特拉娜的文件夹就不仅仅在雷迪的硬盘里了
...then Yogi-Svetlana's folder won't only be in Reddy's hard drive
好吧，我们走
Okay, lets go
混蛋
Assholes
企业家？
Entrepreneurs?
还想让我退出
Telling me to backout
嘿 杰图，别走啊，我还没被说服呢
Hey Jeetu, come on I'm not convinced yet
来说服我，让我退出
Come and convince me that I should backout
说服我啊，混蛋
Convince me asshole
你说什么？
What did you say?
说服我
Convince me
说服你？
Convince you?
让开
Out of the way
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
这个混蛋让我说服他
This motherfucker asked me to convince him
首先我说服了我的妻子，然后是我的父亲，然后是我的家人
First I convinced my wife, then my dad, then my family
这瘪犊子才他妈17岁
Son of a bitch is just 17
混蛋，我的i7-4790k
Motherfucker, my i7-4790k edition
你们是什么人? ，流氓吗？
What are you? some gangsters?
我们不是流氓
We're not gangsters
我们是企业家
We are entrepreneurs, motherfucker
你知道让孩子上幼儿园要花多少钱吗？
You know how much it costs to get your child into junior KG?
你们了解过房屋抵押吗？
Do you have any idea about house mortgaging?
我昨天去了杂货店
I went to the grocery store yesterday
你知道小玉米要多少钱吗？
You know how much does baby corn cost?
每100克120卢比
Rs 120 per 100 grams
哦，天哪，每公斤1200卢比? 该死！
Oh my, Rs 1200 per kg? Damn!
我的需求是什么？
What did I want?
你拿到你的种子基金，我升职，这要求过分吗？
That you get your seed fund and I get my promotion, Is that too much to ask for?
几乎没有任何难度，而且1/4的团队成员已经辞职了
You hardly faced a challenge and 25% percent of the team has resigned already
普尼特，他手机关机了，跟我们有什么关系
Puneet, he has switched off his phone, how is that our fault?
纳文，跟他讲讲道理
Naveen, talk some sense itno him dude
我已经不想说话了，你讲吧
I'm tired of talking now, you should do it
这就是我要支持的团队吗？
Is this the team that I've advocated for?
这位首席执行官参加会议时甚至没有洗澡或梳洗一番
This CEO attends meeting without even taking a shower or freshen up
这位首席运营官满嘴脏话还欺负人
This CEO curses and bullies people
这个首席技术官疯狂砸电脑
This CTO vandalizes the computers
看起来是一个百万美元的团队，为什么还没有人投你们呢？
This seems like a million dollar team, howcome no one has decided to fund you yet?
普尼特，他来了
Puneet, he's coming
好吧，过去的就让它过去吧，只是不要告诉巴德瓦伊
Alright let bygones be bygones, just don't say anything to Bhardwaj
我来说，好吗？
I'll do the talking, okay?
好了，我们走
Okay lets go
你还好吗? ，你看起来很沮丧
Are you alright? you seem gloomy
嗨，对不起，我被电话拖住了
Hi guys, sorry I got stuck on a call
你们怎么样？
How're you guys doing?
很好，先生
Good, sir
曼达尔在哪里...
Where is uhh...
曼达尔身体不适，所以他今天不能参加了
Uhh Manda...uhh Saurabh is unwell actually so he won't be joining us today
好的，没问题
Okay, no problem
安基特，我和纳文谈过了，他们真的想重新谈谈条件
Ankit, I was talking to Naveen and these guys really want to renegotiate the terms
普尼特，你能不参加这次会议吗？
Puneet, can you sit this one out?
我真的很抱歉，但我想直接和他们谈谈
I'm really sorry but I want to talk to the guys directly
所以，如果你能休息一下，那就太好了
So, if you can take a break, it'd be great
我知道这对你来说意义重大，你为你的产品付出了很多
I know this means a lot to you, you've worked very hard on your product
而且，我真的很感激你们所做的努力
And, I really appreciate the amount of hard work that you've put in
但是...
But...
昨晚我和另一队聊了一下然后...
Last night I had a chat with the other team And...
他们现在给了我一个更好的条件
They are offering me a much better deal now
从现在开始我就可以直接拥有那家公司了
From here on I can virtually own that company
所以... 我没有理由不投资他们
So... I have no reason why I shouldn't invest in them
但是你不认为他们的所作所为是违法的吗？
But don't you think sir its.. what they have done is illegal?
就像我们的产品已经注册了专利，应该受到专利法保护……
Like we've got our product registered and there are copywrite laws...
你可以复制一个产品，但你不能复制一个想法
You can copywrite a product but you can't copywrite an idea
在网上销售商品是一个想法
Selling goods online is an idea
但是 Flipkart，Snapdeal，亚马逊，他们都用
But Flipkart, Snapdeal, Amazon they are all selling it
先生，我认为，这对我们非常不公平
I think sir its extremely unfair to us
- 我们做出的努力...-听着伙计们...
-Like we've been working on this for... -Look guys...
作为一个人，我真的为你感到难过
As a human being, I genuinely feel sorry for you
但作为一个投资者，我不能让这种感觉阻碍我
But as an investor, I can't let that feeling come in my way
如果我想做生意，那么我应该为自己的利益着想，对吗？
And if I want to do a business then I ought to look out for my self interest, right?
普尼特从一开始就知道这件事
Sir like, Puneet knew about it since the beginning
我能进来吗，先生？
May I come in, sir?
曼达尔？
Saurabh?
我以为你病了
I thought you were sick
很抱歉你大老远跑来...
Too bad you came all the way because...
我只有坏消息要告诉你
I have nothing but bad news for you
没关系，先生，我可以给您做个演示吗？
Its okay sir, but can I give you a presentation?
演示? 我只是告诉他们我已经下定决心了，没有必要...
Presentation? I just told them that I've made up my mind and there's no point in...
求你了，先生
Please sir
我花了35000卢比买回来的
I spent Rs 35000 to make this presentation
我知道你已经看过了所有的公司文件，但是先生，这个演示将使我们公司上一个台阶
I know you have seen all the company documents but sir this will make our company really big
我只需要两分钟，先生
I'll need just 2 minutes sir
好吧，开始吧
Alright, go ahead
【纳文的团队】作者: 曼达尔
Naveen's Team by Saurabh Mandal
这个团队由4名成员组成
This team consists of 4 members
纳文·班萨尔
Naveen Bansal
杰图德拉·马赫什瓦里
Jitendra Maheshwari
尤吉德拉 · 库马尔 · 潘迪
Yogendra Kumar Pandey
还有我，索拉布 · 曼达尔
And me, Saurabh Mandal
让我们从杰图开始
Let's begin with Jeetu
我们每个人的生活中都有一个知识分子的儿子
All of us have a Mr Sharma's son(*Stereotypical intellectual son) in our life
但是在比卡内尔的政府高中，有一位马赫什瓦里先生的儿子
But in Bikaner's Government high school, there was a Mr Maheshwari's son
杰图德拉·马赫什瓦里
Jitendra Maheshwari
先生，我从来没有看过后街男孩的现场表演
Sir, I've never seen a live performance of Backstreet Boys
但是我看到过杰图写代码
But I've seen Jeetu writing code
连续36小时不睡觉
Continuously for 36 hours, without any sleep
他本可以去美国为 facebook 工作
He could've easily gone to US to work for facebook
但他为了家庭没有离开印度
But he didn't leave India for his family's sake
毕竟他是个顾家的人
Afterall he is a family man
现在，这是他有生以来第一次为了这家创业公司与家人作对
And now for the first time in his life he went against his family for this startup
为什么? 他为什么这么做？
Why? Why did he do it?
尤吉
Yogi
先生，有些人认识的人很少
Sir, some people know very few people
有些人认识的人很多
Some people know most of the people
但是尤吉认识所有人
But Yogi knows everyone
纳文告诉我，当他们访问古吉拉特时，尤吉安排在凌晨4点喝啤酒
Naveen told me that when they visited Gujarat(*Dry state) Yogi arranged for a beer at 4 in the morning
我从尤吉那里学到了很多关于削减成本的知识，而不是在MBA课程学来的
I learned more about Cost cutting from Yogi than from my MBA lectures
他买了一块二十五里拉的蛋糕作为生日礼物
He bought a cake of just Rs. 25 for his birthday
他的平均 gpa 只有5.3(满分10分)
He had a CGPA of just 5.3(out of 10)
但是他年薪220万卢比
But he got a salary package of Rs 2.2 million
如果他在那里工作的话，两年内他就会成为孟买的地区负责人
He would've been the Mumbai regional head in just 2 years had he been working there
但是他为什么要离开他的工作去创业呢？ 为什么他要竭尽全力这个创业公司奋斗？
But then why did he leave his job for this startup? Why is he fighting tooth and nail for this startup?
难道是为了加快脱发？
Only to let his hair fall?
为什么？
Why?
最后
And finally
纳文·班萨尔
Naveen Bansal
我喜欢看电影
I love watching movies
每部电影的结尾都有"由xx指导"的一行字
In the end of every movie, there's director's name written under "A film by"
我过去常常因为看到这个而生气
I used to get angry by seeing that
我是说...
I mean...
演员表演，编剧写剧本，摄影师拍摄
Actor acts, writer writes and cinematographer shoots the film
那么导演做了什么使他得到如此特别的关注呢
Then what does the director do that he gets such a special attention
他所要做的就是做选择，好还是坏
All he has to do is to make a choice Good or bad
但是纳文意识到，选择是生活中最具挑战性的事情
But Naveen has realised me that choices are the most challenging things in life
先生，这整件事都是纳文的主意
Sir, this whole idea is Naveen's
这是他的产品
This is his product
这是他的团队
This is his team
我们都可以为他挡子弹
If there's anyone in this world for whom we all can take a bullet
这就是坐在这里的那位先生
This is the gentleman sitting over here
为了这个团队，他把我们的家庭办公室和他自己的家变成了一个仓库
For this team, he made our home office and his own home was turned itno a warehouse
这就是那个不喜欢自己熨衬衫的人，他现在自愿帮我们洗所有的衣服
This is the man who didn't like to iron his own shirts, who now volunteers to launder all of our clothes
我们所有人都为彼此做出了很多牺牲
All of us have done a lot of sacrifices for each other
但是纳文为了保护我们所做的远不止这些
But Naveen has done a lot more than that to shield us
为什么纳文要这么做？
Why is Naveen doing all this?
我们为什么要这么做？
All of us
为什么我们所有人都对这家创业公司如此执着？
Why all of us are so hell-bent for this startup?
我来告诉你为什么，先生
I'll tell you why sir
因为我们都想到达这里
Because we all want to reach here
我们不会等任何船
And we're not waiting for any boat
我们已经在未知的海洋中漂流
We're already swimming in the sea of unknown
我们早就离开了我们的舒适区
We've already left our comfort zone long ago
现在我们不关心我们将要面对的变化、挑战或牺牲
Now we don't care about the changes, challenges or sacrifices we'll have to face
无论如何
No matter what
我们的队伍会到达这里，奇迹发生的地方
Our team will reach here, where magic happens
你在你的团队里是做什么的？
And what do you do in your team?
先生，我个人没有任何价值
Sir, I don't have any value individually
我是空气
I'm a zero
但是我的加入使公司净值增加了10倍
But the net value increases by 10 times when I add up
你已经说得很清楚了
You've made your point
现在让我把我的观点再强调一下
Now let me make my point very clear
不管哪支队伍来到这里
No matter which team gets here
最终我将塑造他们的想法，让他们成为一个更大的公司
It's ultimately going to be me who's going to shape their idea and make them a bigger company
这需要业务专业知识来构建这些东西
You need business business expertise to build this things
听起来可能很傲慢，但让我告诉你们
And, at the risk of sounding arrogant let me tell you guys that
我选择的团队一定是最强的
The team which I shall support, that team would be the strongest
这个团队必将成为一个更大的公司
And that team will make a bigger company
我想你们忘了，我已经决定投资另一队了
And I think you guys are forgetting that, I've already decided to back the other team
先生，你还忘了一件事
Sir, you're also forgetting something
你的岛不是海里唯一的岛屿
Yours is not the only island in the sea
还有其他神奇的岛屿
There are other magical islands
他们也很愿意拉我们上岸
Who'll be more than happy to have us on the shore
所以你是说...
So you're saying that...
还有其他投资者有投资意向？
You've offers from other investors as well?
先生，你真的认为我们只向一个投资者展示产品吗？
Sir, do you really think that we presented our product to just one investor?
这些投资者到底是谁？
And who are these investors exactly?
对不起，先生，我现在不能透露他们的名字
Sorry sir, I can't reveal their names at this point of time
你们知道我的名声
You know my reputation guys
如果我拒绝你的想法，那么没有人敢在这里给你们投资
If I reject your idea, then no one will dare to invest here with you
先生，你知道我们的毅力
And sir you know our perseverance
我们一定会上岸的
We'll surely make it up to there
无论是在你的投资组合中还是在你的反投资组合中
Either in your portfolio or in your anti-portfolio
我经常玩扑克
I play poker a lot
我一看就知道你是在虚张声势
I know a bluff when I see one
你没有别的选择
You have no other offers
你在利用我害怕失败的心理
You're trying to play on my fear of losing out
事实就是...
When the fact is...
除了我
Apart from me
你无处可去
You've nowhere else to go
好吧，被你识破了
Sir, the ball is still in your court
呆在这儿，曼达尔，你要去哪儿？
Stay here Mandal, where are you going?
不，我要回家
No, I'm going home
我得起草一份正式的辞职信
I have to draft a formal resignation letter
你的“毅力”和“上岸”哪去了？
Whatever happened to your "perseverance" and "making up to the island"?
我们要你留下你还非要走
Now that we're telling you to stay, you're walking out
不，过多的情感依恋是不好的
No, too much emotional attachment is bad
无论发生了什么，都是最好的结果
Whatever happened, happened for the best
坐下，混蛋
Sit-down asshole
你没听见我说话吗，混蛋，回来
Didn't you hear me asshole? come back
如果我是个混蛋，你为什么还要我留下？
Why do you want me to stay if I'm an asshole?
因为你是我的朋友，混蛋
Because you're my friend motherfucker
过来，坐下
Come on now, sit-down here
我不会的
I won't
那只是一个演示，现在不要想逞英雄
It was just a presentation, don't try to be a hero now
我昨天心情不好，回来吧
I was in a black mood yesterday, come on back here
我说了我不会
I said I won't
我知道我昨天反应过度了，试着理解我在说什么
I know I overreacted yesterday, try to understand what I'm saying
理解什么？
understand what?
我说对不起，混蛋
That I'm saying sorry motherfucker
现在给我回来，不然我揍你
Now come back here or I'll whoop your ass
没关系，我原谅你
It's okay I forgive you
我们拿到了
We got it
我们成功了，杰图
We go it Jeetu
我要倒了
Guys put me down
我告诉过你我的U盘能做什么
I told you what my pen drive could do
干杯
Cheers
哥几个，今晚不醉不归
Let's take about 10 such pitchers to home, we'll get some fine quality beer with a lot of froth
我们只有10% 的种子基金，别在文书工作之前搞砸了
We've only got 10% of the seed fund, don't fuck this up before paperwork
这话出自一个最近在青年旅社砸电脑的家伙之口
Says the guy who recently fucked it up in a hostel
不过还是很开心的，不是吗？
It was exhilerating though, wasn't it?
我很生气有一半是因为你砸了我的手机
Half of my frustration was because you broke my phone
把你的手机给我，我要和桑亚说一声
Give me your phone, I need to talk to Soumya
纳文，我觉得我们的新办公室应该在宝威附近
Naveen, I think our new office should be in the vicinity of Powai lake
研究表明，如果你每天早上看到水，你的血细胞会增加12%
The research says that if you see water every morning, your blood cells are tend to increase by 12%
我们付不起那的房租，混蛋
We can hardly afford 1 BHK there fucker
我们需要网络运维，杰图需要程序员，我们需要一个办公室室，我需要一个实习生
We need someone for UYOS, Jeetu needs a developer, we need an office setup, I need an intern
别担心，我们的首席执行官班萨尔先生会给我们一切
Don't worry, our CEO Mr. Bansal will give us everything. We'll get everything
没有人能得到一切，兄弟
No one ever gets everything dude
有些东西注定不属于你
There are some things which are never meant to be yours
你最近到底怎么了？
What the hell happened to you?
没什么，我开玩笑的
No nothing, I'm just kidding
好了，你们慢用，我要打个电话
Okay you guys enjoy, I need to make a phone call
纳文，你好
Naveen? hi
嘿 拉索尔，你好吗？
Hey Rathore, how are you bro?
我很好，你呢？
I'm doing great, what about you?
你现在是大四吧，你在这里做什么？
You were in final year, what are you doing here?
不，不，我去年毕业的，我现在在这里工作
No no, I graduated last year I have a job here now
太好了，你长大了
That's great. you've grown up
不，伙计，你才是那个成功人士
No dude, you're the one who's doing great
我有关注你的Facebook状态
I just liked your facebook status
哦，那么你知道了？
Oh, so you know about it?
恭喜你，老哥，你成功了
Congratulations man, you aced it
我现在非常嫉妒你
I'm feeling very jealous from you right now
你的未来一定会很精彩
Your life is gonna be awesome dude
而我们只能在办公室填写 excel 表格
While we will only get to fill excel sheets in our office
只有周末可以放松一下
I've only got weekends to enjoy
虽然我也想过开一家创业公司，但我没有足够的时间
Although I also thought about opening a startup but I couldn't give it enough time
即使我有足够的时间，也没有你的运气
And even if I got enough time, nobody's luck is as good as yours
回答我一个问题
Tell me one thing...
你是什么？
What are you?